A Finding Aid to the Ben Shahn Papers, 1879-1990, bulk 1933-1970, in the Archives of American Art AAA.shahben
Archives of American Art
- Letters, 1929-1990; Series 2; 14.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-25, 35, OVs 36-38
  - L, Miscellaneous: L. - Lar, 1949-1969 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Las - Laz, 1935-1969 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Le - Lep, 1935-1968 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lep - Ley, 1941-1968 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lib - Lie, 1951-1968 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lif - Liv, 1955-1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Loc - Lon, 1948-1967 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lor - Loz, 1945-1968 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    oversized material housed in Box 35
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lu - Ly, 1957-1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - L, Miscellanous, Posthumous, 1969-1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - L, First Names Only, 1950-1967 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - MacLeish, Ada and Archibald, circa 1955-1968, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - MacMillan Company, 1961-1970 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Mandel, Estelle, circa 1953-1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Mann, Theodore, circa 1959-1964 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Margolis, Mars and William N., circa 1958-1971 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Marin, John, Jr., and Norma (see also Downtown Gallery), circa 1956-1969 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Martin, David Stone and Gloria, 1955-1960 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Martin, John Bartlow, 1948-1963, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    see also Box 19 Folder 5
  - Martini, Alberto and Paolo, circa 1957-1965 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Mason, Mary, circa 1962-1967 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1954-1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Massachusetts Review, 1962-1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Matisse, Paul, circa 1957-1964 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - May, Rollo, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Mayer, Bena and Ralph, 1947-1967 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - McCann-Erickson, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1958-1966 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Medical Press, Inc., 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo (Festival of Two Worlds), 1959-1966, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Mercey, Arch and Elena, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Meriden Gravure Company, circa 1952-1965 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Messages For Peace, 1965-1969; 4 Folders (Box 18, Folder 29-32)
    partially scanned
  - Metropolitan Art Association of Detroit, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1941-1962, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Miami University, 1953-1963 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Michigan State College, 1950-1956 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Middlebury College, 1952-1958 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Milwaukee Art Institute, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1953-1958 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Minneapolis School of Art, 1953-1965 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Moomey, Bill, circa 1950-1954 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1948-1963 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Motive Magazine, 1947-1960 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Munson-Williams Proctor Institute, circa 1953-1965 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Mural Painters (Society), 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Murphy, James, 1945-1959 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Museum of African Art (Warren Robbins), 1962-1974 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    (includes photograph of Robbins)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (and School), 1947-1963 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1964-1977 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Museum of Modern Art, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1932-1947 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1948-1950 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1951-1953 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1956-1959 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1965-1969 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - Museum Tel Aviv, 1954-1956 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Museum of the City of New York, 1956-1958, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - M, Miscellaneous: M. - Man, 1943-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Marc - Marq, 1953-1968 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mars - May, 1953-1968 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mc - Mel, 1950-1969 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mem - Mey, 1941-1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mia - Mil, 1952-1968 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Min - Miz, 1944-1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mob - Mon, 1949-1968 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Moo - Moy, 1935-1969 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    (includes accoung of attending the funeral of Sacco and Vanzetti written by Hannah Moore, daughter of Thomas Gregory Connolly, whom Moore claims was Sacco and Vanzetti's first attorney)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mu - My, 1952-1969 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - M, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1969-1989 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - M, First Names Only, 1953-1967 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - M, Illegible, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - N. W. Ayer & Son, 1943-1965 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Nakashima, George and Marion, circa 1954-1969, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    (includes letter from Bernarda Bryson written from Tokyo describing her's and Shahn's impressions of Japan)
  - Nantenshi Gallery, 1970-1977, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Nation, 1952-1965 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - National Academy of Design, 1946-1965 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 1955-1965 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1953-1965 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (also includes local councils and committees), circa 1959-1967 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1957-1967 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - National Educational Television, 1963-1968 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - National Gallery of Art, circa 1941-1968 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, circa 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1959-1963 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1964-1968 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - National Society of Arts and Letters, circa 1964-1966 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Nationalmuseum (Carl Nordenfalk), 1960-1965 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Neiman-Marcus, 1949-1966 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Neuberger, Marie and Roy R., circa 1946-circa 1963 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - New Directions, circa 1951-1969, 1985-1988 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - New Jersey Society of Architects, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - New Republic, 1948, 1961-1968, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - New School (for Social Research), 1955-1968 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - New York Graphic Society, 1956-1968, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    (includes 1963 letter from Shahn)
  - New York Public Library, circa 1941-1964 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - New York Times, 1952-1968 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - New York University, circa 1954-1966 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Newark Museum, 1944-1966 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Nipp, Francis and Mary Ellen, 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Nordness Gallery, 1962-1966 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Northwestern University, 1953-1967, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - N, Miscellaneous, Nac - Nath, 1947-1969 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - N, Miscellaneous, National A - National C, 1950-1968 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - N, Miscellaneous, National E - Nav, circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    (includes letter from Shahn to Nations Business)
  - N, Miscellaneous, Neb - Nev, 1957-1968 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - N, Miscellaneous, New American - New Yorker, 1947-1969 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - N, Miscellaneous, Newall - Newton, 1949-1968 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    (includes letter from Barnett Newman)
  - N, Miscellaneous, Ni - No, 1951-1969 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - N, Miscellanous, Posthumous, 1971-1988 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - N, First Names Only, 1960-1968 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - O'Neal, Hank, circa 1960s, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Obelisco Galleria d'Arte, 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Odets, Clifford, circa 1949-1952 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Odyssey Press, Inc. (see also Risom, Ole), 1964-1968 (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Ohio State University/Ohio State University Press, 1950-1967, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Ohio University, 1951-1965 (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Old Queens Gallery, 1963-1967, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Olivetti, see: Soavi, Giorgio (Box 19)
  - Olson, Charles and Kate, circa 1946-1952, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Opera News, 1960-1962 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Orion Press, 1963-1971, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1947-1953 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1950s; 2 Folders (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1952-1962 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1960s (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1963-1966 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1947-1969 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - O, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1970-1988 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - P. M., circa 1940-1946 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Pagnani, Roberto, 1956-1963 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Pantheon Books (see also Coen, Fabio and Silvane), 1951-1968; 2 Folders (Box 20, Folder 18-19)
  - Paone, Barbara and Peter, circa 1959-1968 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Parry, Marian and Maury, circa 1948-1959 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Parvey, Constance, circa 1966-1968, 1985-1987 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Pearson, Ralph M., 1935, 1950-1952 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Penguin Books, 1947-1968 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Pembroke Gallery, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, circa 1939-1967 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Pennsylvania State College, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1956-1968 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Perlin, Bernard, circa 1944-1953 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Perspecta, Yale Architectural Journal, 1956-1958 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1943-1967 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Philadelphia Museum College of Art, circa 1955-1962 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1950-1971 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Pickett, Clarence E., 1958-1963 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Pineles, Bill and Cipe, circa 1945-1957 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Pineles, Bill and Cipe, 1958-1968 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Pines, David and Suzy, circa 1954-1969 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Plaut Travel Inc., 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Playhouse in the Park, 1963-1966 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Plunguian, Gina, circa 1951-1957 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Pohl, Frances, 1979-1988 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Polonsky, Arthur, 1947-1949, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Portfolio, circa 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Poster Originals, Ltd., 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Pozzatti, Doti and Rudy, 1950-1971 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Prakapas Gallery, 1977-1987 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Pratt Graphics Center, 1958-1974 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Pratt Institute, 1952-1967 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Prevention of Blindness Society of Metropolitan Washington, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1954-1955 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Princeton Day School, circa 1962-1966 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Princeton Group Arts, 1952-circa 1961 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Princeton University, circa 1954-1962 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Princeton University, circa 1963-1978 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    (includes University Art Museum)
  - Princeton University Press, 1966-1968 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Print, 1949-1958 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Print Club, circa 1951-1968 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Print Council of America, 1957-1965 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - Pulga, Bruno, 1956-1964 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pa, 1948-1968 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pe, 1943-1969 (Box 20, Folder 61)
    (includes letter from Shahn to Donald Pelsue about artists point of view re. "the public need for new values")
  - P, Miscellaneous: Ph, 1951-1968 (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pi, 1943-1968 (Box 20, Folder 63)
    (includes 1950 letter from Pablo Picasso)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pl, 1952-1968 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Po, 1950-1969 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pra - Pri, 1949-1968 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    (includes letter illustrated with a watercolor by artist named Pribil)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pro - Pu, 1940-1969 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - P, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1969-1988 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - P, First Names Only, 1947-1966 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - P, Illegible, circa 1956-1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Q, Miscellaneous, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Rachel Productions, circa 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Ramparts, circa 1966-1969 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Randolph-Macon Woman's College, 1959-1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Random House, Inc., 1961-1967 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Rathbone Books, 1959-1962 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Reitman, Alan, 1947-1959 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1956-1966 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Richter, Irving, circa 1950, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Riker's Island Prison Mural, circa 1935 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Riker's Island Prison Mural, Photographs and Reproductions, circa 1935 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Risom, Ole (Odyssey Press), 1962-1968 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    (includes 1962 letter from Shahn)
  - Rivera, Diego, circa 1933-1957 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    (includes letter from Nelson A. Rockefeller regarding Lenin's head in 1933 Rockefeller Center mural and draft of Rivera's response)
  - Riznik, Joseph Q., circa 1955-1964 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Robbins, Jerome, circa 1957-1968 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Robbins, Warren, see: Museum of African Art and Center for Cross-Cultural Communication in C, Miscellaneous, Posthumous (Box 21)
  - Roberts, Kay, 1965-1967 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Rodman, Selden, circa 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1951-1955 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1956-1972 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Roosevelt Memorial Association, 1961-1966 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Roosevelt, New Jersey, Centennial, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1956-1971 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    (includes photocopy of 1971 letter from Shahn)
  - Rosskam, Edwin, 1947-1967 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Roston, Arnold, circa 1963-1968, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Roth, Cecil and Irene, 1963-1967 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Roth, Lee and Wolfgang, circa 1950-1969 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Rowan, Edward B., circa 1943-1945 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Ruder, Finn and Fujita Inc., circa 1956-1965 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Rutgers University, 1956-1971, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Ruttenberg, Harold J., 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - R, Miscellaneous: R. - Ra, 1949-1969 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    (includes photocopy of a letter from Shahn to Henry A. Raemsch about proces of mural painting; includes 2 letters from Robert Rauschenberg)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rea - Rei, 1948-1969 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    (includes letter from Shahn to Herbert Read)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rel - Rh, 1952-1969 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ri, 1938-1968 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rob - Roe, 1948-1969 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rof - Roo, 1953-1967 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    (includes 1958 letter from Eleanor Roosevelt)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ros - Roy, 1939-1969 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ru - Ry, 1942-1967 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - R, Miscellanous, Posthumous, 1969-1986 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - R, First Names Only, 1954-1963 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - R, Illegible, 1943-1965 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Sackheim, Ben, circa 1956-1969 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    (includes photos of Sackheim with David Alfaro Siqueiros and Angelica Arenal Siqueiros)
  - Sackowitz, Isidore, circa 1959-1968 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Saint Louis Post-Dispatch, 1953-1956 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Saint Paul Art Center, 1961-1966 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Saint Paul's School, 1953-1956 (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1952-1967, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - Schary, Dore, 1952-1969 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    (includes draft of a letter from Shahn)
  - Schocken Books Inc., 1962-1966 (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Scholastic Magazines, Inc., 1955-1964, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - Schulman & Bressler, see: Bressler, Martin (Box 21)
  - Schulman, Jacob, 1953-1969, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Schwartz, Aubrey, 1955-circa 1962 (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Schwartz, Tony, circa 1954-1962 (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Scientific American, 1949-1966 (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - Seckler, Dorothy, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - Seligman, Pearl, circa 1949-1963 (Box 21, Folder 61)
    (includes letter from Bernarda Bryson Shahn)
  - Seventeen, 1949-1963 (Box 21, Folder 62)
    (includes 1954 letter from Shahn)
  - Seymour Lawrence Incorporated, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Shahn, Abigail, circa 1940s-1968 (Box 21, Folder 64)
    (includes 1963 artwork by Abigail Shahn)
  - Shahn, Ben and Bernarda Bryson, circa 1962-1969 (Box 21, Folder 65)
    (includes only 6 items all from Bernarda Bryson Shahn except for an illustrated greeting to an unknown recipient from Ben and Bernarda Shahn)
  - Shahn, Ezra and Joyce, 1937-1965 (Box 21, Folder 66)
  - Shahn, Jonathan, 1950s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Shahn, Judith, 1930s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 68)
  - Shahn, Judith, 1937-1959 (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - Shahn, Judith, 1960-1968 (Box 21, Folder 70)
  - Shahn Watts, Susannah, 1940s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 71)
  - Shahn Watts, Susannah, 1952-1966 (Box 21, Folder 72)
  - Shahn, Tillie Goldstein, circa 1935-1946 (Box 21, Folder 73)
  - Shan, Bertha and Philip, 1942-1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Shapiro, Saul, 1955-1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Shaw, Harold, 1952-1958 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    (includes fragment of 1953 letter from Shahn)
  - Shorewood Publishers Inc., 1959-1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Show, 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Simmons, Mike, 1934-1956 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1956-1962 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1952-1960 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, circa 1960s-1964 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1965-1968 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1971-1988 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Reports and Minutes of Meetings, 1962-1988; 2 Folders (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
  - Slee, John Ledyard Fletcher, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Smith College, 1948-1970 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Smith William A., 1962-1968 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Soavi, Giorgio, 1965-1969, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Soby, James Thrall and Melissa, circa 1945-1954 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Soby, James Thrall and Melissa, 1955-1971 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Society of Illustrators, 1946-1970 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Soewarjono, Dan, 1960-1963 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc. (formerly Southern Conference for Human Welfare), 1945-1959 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc., 1960-1970 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Soyer, Moses and Raphael, circa 1947-1969 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Spagnoli, Luisa, 1956-1966 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    (includes illustrated card)
  - Spiral Press (Joseph Blumenthal), circa 1951-1957 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Spiral Press (Joseph Blumenthal), 1958-1970 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Spivak, Dorothy and Sydney, circa 1946-1967 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Staatliche Kunsthalle Baden-Baden, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - State of New Jersey, Commission to Study Arts in New Jersey, Reports and Minutes of Meetings, 1962-1966 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - State of New Jersey, Department of Education, 1953-1965 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - State of New Jersey, Department of Education, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - State of New Jersey, Department of Education, 1967-1980 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - State of New Jersey, Office of the Governor, circa 1960-1968 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - State of New Jersey, Tercentenary Commission, 1961-1965 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - State University of Iowa, 1945-1958 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Stedelijk Museum, 1953-1967, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren, 1952-1963 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Stillman, Bud and Mary, circa 1950s-1969 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Stryker, Roy (see also USDA, Farm Security Administration), 1940-1964 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Swarthmore College, 1952-1964 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1953-1965 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Syracuse University, 1958-1966 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    (includes 1966 letter from Shahn)
  - Syracuse University, 1967-1985 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - S, Miscellaneous: S. - Sak, 1944-1967 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sal - Sax, 1949-1969 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    (includes letter from Carl Sandburg enclosing a poem written by Sandburg "for Ben Shahn-in fellowship")
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sca - Schn, 1934-1969 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Scho - Sco, 1949-1969 (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Se, 1953-1968 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    oversized material - illustrated letter from Erica Selig - housed in OV 38
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sha - Shel, 1949-1968 (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Shen - Shw, 1949-1969 (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Si, 1948-1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sk - Sn, 1940-1967 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - S, Miscellaneous: So, 1947-1969 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sp, 1955-1967 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sta, 1951-1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Ste - Sti, 1954-1968 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sto - Stu, 1947-1968 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Su - Sz, 1956-1969 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - S, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1969-1989 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - S, First Names Only, 1949-1973 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    (includes letters from "Sally," apparently a relative of Bernarda Bryson Shahn and a copy of a letter written by Bernarda Shahn regarding family history and property in Ohio; includes letter to "Sidney" from Shahn)
  - S, Illegible, Unidentified, circa 1956-1969 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Tagliabue, John, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Takach, Mary, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Taller, Stephen Lee, 1984-1988 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Temple Emanu-El, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Temple Isaiah, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Terra Museum of American Art, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1956-1969 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Thompson, Estelle, circa 1947-circa 1950 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Time, circa 1944-1968, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Timothy Dwight College, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Trianon Press, circa 1958-1962 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Trianon Press, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Trianon Press, 1965-1983 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Trinity College, 1961-1965 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - T, Miscellaneous: T. - Tam, 1948-1967 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tan - Tay, 1953-1969 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tea - Tem, 1955-1969 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ten - Th, 1947-1968 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ti - Tra, 1950-1966 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tre - Tw, 1948-1968 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - T, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1969-1986 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - T, First Names Only, circa 1956-1968 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1948-1972 (Box 23, Folder 34)